

# **Ross Condie**

## Junior Full-Stack Engineer

As a curious and driven Full-Stack Engineer I am eager to advance my skills and step into a technical role. Through a diverse range of life and work experience with over a decade in the service industry, I bring a unique attitude to my development work. This outlook motivates me to consistently improve, while my persistent attention to detail ensures I am thorough in my approach. In addition I excel collaborating within a team.

rosscondie@gmail.com

Hannover, Germany

in linkedin.com/in/rosscondie

015129602494

www.rosscondie.com

github.com/rosscondie

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

Languages

Python, JavaScript, Java

Frameworks

React/React Native, Express, Spring,

Tailwind CSS

**Databases** MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Tools

Git/Github, Visual Studio Code, IntelliJ

Remotely delivered

Edinburgh, Scotland

IDEA

Methodologies Agile, Waterfall, Iterative Development,

TDD, Pair Programming

## **EDUCATION**

# **Professional Software Development**CodeClan Digital Skills Academy

01/2023 - 05/2023

Object-Orientated Programming

RESTful Routing

Databases

Full Stack Development

○ Intro to Web Development - UI/UX

Version Control

Test Driven Development

Paired & Mob Programming

# **HND Sound Production** Edinburgh College

09/2007 - 06/2009

Multi-track Recording and Mixing
Sound Design & Game Audio

Audio Post-Production

Creative Music Re-Mixing

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### Constructed a Personal Portfolio website. (04/2023 - Present)

- Github Ross Condie Personal Portfolio This was a solo project created using JavaScript, React and CSS.
- I wanted to learn more about responsive web design by building something useful to showcase my personal projects.
- Discovered how to use media queries to make my web application more responsive to tablet and mobile devices.
- Using custom CSS variables to define values to be reused throughout my application which saved time and kept the colour theme consistent.

#### Recreated a popular ride-hailing mobile application. (04/2023 - 05/2023)

- Uber Clone Capstone This was a paired project created using React Native, Redux & Tailwind CSS.
- Learned completely new frameworks and libraries (React Native & Redux) within a two week time frame. Incorporating Google Cloud API's such as Places/Directions & Distance Matrix API's.
- Efficiently pair-programmed over the whole project, running daily meetings to merge changes to Github.
- Implemented a tipping feature that could improve user experience within the app.



Built a full-stack web application for a portfolio of stocks and shares. (03/2023 - 03/2023)

- Atlas Wealth This was a group project built with JavaScript, React, Express, MongoDB & MaterialUI.
- Gained experience working on a group project with three other developers building a full-stack web application over a one week period.
- Working with agile methodologies such as daily standup's and kanban board planners to debug and resolve conflict merges.
- Researched JavaScript libraries and became familiar with understanding how to effectively read documentation.

### Created a web application to track travel adventures. (02/2023 - 03/2023)

- Fugitive Travel This was a solo project CRUD application created using Python, HTML, CSS, Flask & PostrgreSQL.
- Comprehensive understanding of CRUD operations and their benefits.
- Learned to implement a static web application with a fully functioning back-end server database. Consolidating 4 weeks of learning into a one week project.
- Researched into following RESTful routing conventions.



## WORK EXPERIENCE

## Senior Barber/Stylist

Surf N' Cut

03/2021 - 12/2022 Hannover, Germany

- Established a new client base building relationships with clients by consistently providing exceptional service with quality work.
- Ocliaborated with clients to evaluate personal preferences and individual requirements.
- Implemented and applied new skills to enhance daily operations, resulting in improved efficiency and productivity.
- Learned conversational German through meeting and interacting with clients.

# Senior Barber/Stylist

Rag and Bone

11/2016 - 03/2021 Edinburah, Scotland

- Built strong and lasting rapport with clients through consistent delivery of requested services with exceptional results.
- Consulted with clients to assess personal preferences and unique needs.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and in a fast paced environment.
- Supervised over training sessions of employees.



## **CERTIFICATES**

Professional Development Award in Software Development (01/2023 - 05/2023)

Scottish Qualifications Authority (SCQF Level 8)

Decarbonising Digital - Digital Sustainability (08/2023)

GoCodeGreen Learning Academy, Decarbonising Digital - Digital Sustainability Foundation Course

TELC German A1 (01/2022 - 01/2022)

DKH Sprachschule - Deutsch A1 Zertifikat

HarvardX - CS50x (06/2023 - Present)

Harvard CS50's Introduction to Computer Science

Responsive Web Design - freeCodeCamp (07/2023)

Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework.



**Problem Solving** 

Time Management

Flexibility

Adaptability

Communication

**Conflict Resolution** 

Creativity

Attention to Detail

**Dependability** 



English



German











Programming



Photography



Video Games

